## AISHWARYA KALBURGI

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

## CONTACT

8073592311

aishwaryakalburgi990@gmail.com

https://aishwarya1-1.github.io/aishwarya/

5th cross Bhagyanagar Belgaum 560009

## **TECHNOLOGIES**

- Python
- PySpark
- Flask
- Linux
- AWS Services
- · MySQL and NoSQL
- Git
- Java & Kotlin(Beginner)
- · Data Structures and Algorithms
- Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
- ELK Stack (Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana)
- Web technology:REACT

\_\_\_\_\_

## EDUCATION

#### **BACHELORS DEGREE**

B.E – B V Bhoomaraddi College Of Engineering & Technology

2013-2017

- Created a management system for the college database in the form of a GUI using JAVA and MySQL
- Designed and implemented an online results system for college
- Worked on developing a hand gesture controlled game in unity 3D integrated with OpenCV
- Worked on developing an Optimized face recognition system using Gabor filter and SVM classifier

PRE-UNIVERSITY

#### **CHETAN PU-COLLEGE HUBLI**

2011-2013

### LANGUAGES

English	
Kannada	
Hindi	

#### PROFILE

As a seasoned Software Engineer with 5.9 years of experience in the Information Technology (IT) sector, I have cultivated a deep passion for crafting software solutions. My enthusiasm drives me to stay up-to date with the latest technologies and continuously enhance my skill set, enabling me to contribute effectively within collaborative team environments. I eagerly look forward to applying my expertise and passion to have a profound impact on customers.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **CLOUD AND AUTOMATION ENGINEER**

## **MICROFOCUS**

2017-2021

- Led a project utilising the ELK stack to retrieve, process, and create visualizations in Kibana for Micro Focus Pre-sales data.
- Worked on developing banking use cases (securitization, demand draft), testing, and defect fixing for the Westpac Banking application.
- Streamlined the process of building a Linux-based infrastructure and integrated it with Vcenter, Server Automation, and Operations Bridge Manager(OBM) within the Operation Orchestration tool
- Automated the generation of Workday expense Report through RPA (Robotic Process Automation) and UFT.
- Experience in working with REST APIs
- Contributed to ChatBot Development for Sungard customer
- Setting deeper log levels and troubleshooting 00 logs for issues
- · Worked on Netsuite APIs for P2P processing
- Automated the VM resource Utilisation summary generation in a excel worksheet with Python scripting
- Worked on building functionality & APIs to establish E-bonding between two incident management applications
- Enhanced workflow efficiency through automation. Tracked path usage within
  workflows to decide on path retention. Used Operations Orchestration for
  automation and integrated with Business Value Dashboard for clear performance
  insights
- Automated the generation of daily status report sent to the Westpac banking client containing a snapshot of the application's performance and activities for that day, including details about successful transactions, errors encountered, metrics and highlighted spikes
- Developed utilities for basic Elastic Search CRUD operations in OO tool

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

2021-2022

## **PRODAPT**

- Developed a dynamic SNMP query utility in Python using argparse and PySNMP libraries, enabling retrieval of specific information from remote devices for network management. Transformed it into a standalone application using PyInstaller for easy distribution
- Replaced the file-based approach with an API-based approach when directing information to ESP(Event Stream Processing), a component of Assure1, for data handling
- Exposure to concepts such as the Go programming language and Microservices, as well as technologies like Assure1

# AISHWARYA KALBURGI

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **SUPPORT ENGINEER LEVEL 2**

## **AMAZON**

2022-present

#### **Amazon Academy**

- Implemented functionality and provided a user interface to clone content packs, establish bidirectional
  mappings of multiple offering IDs with content packs, facilitate the removal of offering IDs from
  content packs, and viewing offering IDs and content pack associations. This resulted in substantial
  reductions in manual workload for the content team, reducing a day long task ,with zero manual errors.
  Leveraged multiprocessing concepts for efficient bulk mapping and integrated with DynamoDB and
  ElasticSearch to retrieve offering ID data. Technology utilised: Flask.
- Implemented validations on daily digest (tip of the day) fields to eliminate delivery of blank/incorrect
  content for a specific day to the students using Java and Bash scripting. Also came up with a
  mechanism to update the Daily digest bundle.
- Automated solution to validate availability of all artifacts (DPP, Classnotes, watch recordings) for each session in the Live Lectures component of AA and notify teachers via email, as well as ensuring accuracy of content pack mapping. Technologies: Flask, S3, AppConfig, IAM.

#### Kindle accounting and royalty

- Worked on taking care of accounting launches and tech debts for Ebooks and Kindle Unlimited Business
- Automated the generation of Accounting Rollforward report for the Kindle Unlimited business utilising Datanet and Spark technologies. Received stakeholder appreciation for aligning with one of Amazon's leadership principles
- Developed a new reporting solution to automate the generation of Accounting Aging reports for Kindle
  Unlimited subscriptions. This solution leveraged various AWS services, including AWS Glue, Lambda,
  and a Redshift database, and was implemented using AWS CDK. The ETL process was facilitated using
  Datanet ETL Jobs to load raw data into an internal Redshift cluster. Data transformation and
  processing were performed using PySpark, while the reporting solution itself was developed in Kotlin.
- Addressed a significant financial impact of approximately one \$1MM resulting from unbooked transactions in the accounting ledger,falling under a specific bucket of non-payment. Formulated rules and use cases within Axon to efficiently process those accounting events originating from upstream sources
- Performed redrives for reducing unbooked impact
- Experinced in ticket handling including sev 2 tickets and engaged in on-call responsibilities. Worked on resolving risks and weblab removal